Casey Reyes

Santa Clara, CA ♦ Email ♦ Portfolio ♦ LinkedIn

Highly motivated software developer with five years of experience in the software industry and a passion for software engineering. Skilled in web applications, software development, and scripting. Possesses excellent interpersonal skills, a solutions-oriented mindset, and the ability to work on multiple tasks or projects either independently or as part of a team.

EXPERIENCE

Bitwise Industries

React Developer Apprentice

Oakland, CA

2022 - Present

Underwent rigorous hands-on training through immersive classroom experiences and working alongside experienced developers to support actual clients

- See Foundations Suit Drive
- See Capstone Project: Spotify clone music player
- See Neon Weather API Web App

Cadence Design Systems

Product Engineer

2020 - 2020

San Jose, CA

- Designed, developed and tested automation scripts for both customers and internal use
- Performed regression tests to ensure developed systems continue to function after any changes

National Instruments

Senior Software Technician (Full-Time beginning 2018)

Santa Clara, CA

2016 - 2020

- Refactored a critical Tier-1 customer legacy software system that improved efficiency by 90%
- Worked with the Lead Architect to design, develop, and test scripts using Visual Basic for internal use

PROJECTS

Foundations Suit Drive | Live Site

- Deployed client event web page using WordPress and PHP, contributing to successful project delivery
- Leveraged Gutenberg blocks to create visually appealing and customizable content
- Expanded functionality and design of custom themes using PHP, SASS, and Bootstrap, resulting in enhanced user experience and seamless integration of desired features for the client

Capstone Project: Spotify clone music player | GitHub Repo

- Independently reimagined Spotify using their API with technologies like TypeScript, React, Express, React Three Fiber for visualizations, and Redux
- Implemented well-optimized front-end UI architecture with an emphasis on performance and robust monitoring

Neon Weather API Web App | GitHub Repo

- Reviewed application requirements and interface designs
- Built accessible and reusable components

EDUCATION

San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering, Minor in Mathematics

San Jose, CA

May 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS & INTERESTS

Languages: Visual Basic, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, TypeScript, Python, C++, Java, PHP, Swift, Objective-C

Technologies/Frameworks: React, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Jest, Firebase, WordPress, Figma, Tailwind, SASS

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, VS Code, Visual Studio, Google Cloud Platform, WPEngine

Libraries: Redux Toolkit, Axios, Styled-Components, Three.js

Interests: Dogs; yoga; travelling; beer; video games; anime; horror shows; music; DJing; Stormlight Archive